Guide to the Tony Judt Papers MC 233
New York University Archives
- Series II: Articles/Essays
  - Subseries A: Notes, Drafts and Research
    - "What is Living and What is Dead in Social Democracy?" NYR, 2009 (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - "Words," NYR, 2010 (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - "Three Memoirs," NYR, 2010 (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - "Lucky Breaks," NYR, 2010 (Box 16, Folder 30)
    - "Crossings," NYR, 2010 (Box 16, Folder 31)
    - "Historian's Progress," NYR, 2010 (Box 16, Folder 32)
    - "Three More Memoirs," NYR, 2010 (Box 16, Folder 33)
    - "On Being Austere and Being Jewish," NYR, 2010 (Box 16, Folder 34)
    - "Open Letter About ALS," NYR, 2010 (Box 16, Folder 35)
    - "Meritocrats," NYR, 2010 (Box 16, Folder 36)
    - "Voyage Home," NYR, 2010 (Box 16, Folder 37)
    - "The Glory of the Rails," NYR, 2010 (Box 16, Folder 38)
    - "What is to Be Done?" The Guardian, 2010 (Box 16, Folder 39)
    - "Derus alkony," Irodalmi es Tarsadalmi Havi Lap, 2010 (Box 16, Folder 40)
    - "Bring Back the Rails!" NYR, 2011 (Box 16, Folder 41)
  - Subseries B: Reprints
    - "The Development of Socialism in France: The Example of the Var," The Historical Journal, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 42)
    - "The origins of rural socialism in Europe: economic change and the Provencal peasantry, 1870-1914," Social History, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 43)
    - "The French Socialist and the Cartel des Gauches of 1924," Journal of Contemporary History, 11, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 44)
    - "Introduction," Journal of Contemporary History, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 45)
    - "Socialism in the French Countryside: A Reply," The Historical Journal, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 46)
    - "Minerva's Owl and Other Birds of Prey," International Labor and Working Class History, 1979 (Box 16, Folder 47)
    - "On the Syntax of the History of Socialism," The Historical Journal, 1979 (Box 16, Folder 48)
    - "The Rules of the Game," review of books on peasant revolutions, The Historical Journal, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 49)
    - "Une historiographie pas comme les autres: The French Communists and their History," European Studies Review, 1982 (Box 16, Folder 50)
    - "Class Composition and Social Structure of Socialist Parties after the First World War: France's Case," Annali della Fondazione Giangiacomo Feltrinelli, 1983-1984 (Box 16, Folder 51)
    - Review of Edouard Vaillant: La creation de l'unite socialiste en France, Journal of Modern History, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 52)
    - "The Spreading Notion of the Town: Some Recent Writings on French and Italian Communism," The Historical Journal, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 53)
    - Review of The Pletzl of Paris, European History Quarterly, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 54)
    - "The ambivalence of emancipation," review of The Jews in Modern France, Patterns of Prejudice, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 55)
    - "Radical Politics in a New Key?" Northwestern University Law Review, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 56)
    - Review of Les vendanges de la République, Journal of Modern History, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 57)
    - Review of Intellectuels français, intellectuels hongrois: XIIIe-XXe siecles, Journal of Modern History, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 58)
    - "The Mitterrand Transition," Dissent, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 59)
    - "The Rediscovery of Central Europe," Daedalus, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 60)
    - Review of The Fourth Republic, 1944-1958, Journal of Modern History, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 61)
    - Review of 2 books on 20th century French politics, Journal of Modern History, Volume 62, Number 4, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 62)
    - Review of Mai 68: L'Entre-deux de la modernité; Histoire de trente ans., American Historical Review, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 63)
    - Review of Syndicalism in France, French History, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 63)
    - Review of The Generation: The Rise and Fall of the Jewish Communists of Poland, Canadian-American Slavic Studies, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 64)
    - "'We Have Discovered History': Defeat, Resistance, and the Intellectuals in France," Journal of Modern History, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 65)
    - "The Past is Another Country," Daedalus, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 66)
    - Review of Paul Lafargue and the Founding of French Marxism, Journal of Modern History, 1993 September (Box 16, Folder 67)
    - "Réponse à Jean-Marie Domenach," Commentaire, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 68)
    - "The Social Question Redivivus," Foreign Affairs, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 69)
    - "Assigning Responsibility: a Note on Daniel Goldhagen's book," Rechtshistorisches Journal, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 70)
    - "Sich Selbst der Schlimmste Feind," Merkur, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 71)
    - "Was vir zu verlieren haben," Merkur, 2006 (Box 16, Folder 72)
    - "Europa gegen Amerika," Merkur, 2005 (Box 16, Folder 73)
    - "Qu'y a-t-il de vivant et qu'y a-t-il de mort dans la social-démocratie?" Commentaire, 2010 (Box 16, Folder 74)
- Series III: Subject Files
  This series contains research files that did not appear to be connected to any of Judt's specific works. Many of the folder titles are Judt's, but some material was loose or unlabeled and so new folder titles were created. These files contain annotated clippings, printouts and photocopies of articles. There are also annotated typescripts and other loose documents not written by Judt.
  - Academic Reading, circa 2009 (Box 16, Folder 75)
  - Academic Reading, circa 2009 (Box 16, Folder 76)
  - Academic Reading, circa 2009 (Box 16, Folder 77)
  - Academic Reading, circa 2009 (Box 16, Folder 78)
  - Academic Reading, circa 2009 (Box 16, Folder 79)
  - Academic Reading, circa 2009 (Box 16, Folder 80)
  - Academic Reading, circa 2009 (Box 16, Folder 81)
  - Academic Reading, circa 2009 (Box 16, Folder 82)
  - Academic Reading, circa 2009 (Box 16, Folder 83)
  - Academic Reading, circa 2009 (Box 16, Folder 84)
  - Academic Reading, circa 2009 (Box 16, Folder 85)
  - Academic Reading, circa 2009 (Box 16, Folder 86)
  - ADL-International, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 87)
  - ADL-International, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 88)
  - ADL-U.S.A., 2002 (Box 16, Folder 89)
  - ADL-U.S.A., 2002 (Box 16, Folder 90)
  - ADL-U.S.A., 2002 (Box 16, Folder 91)
  - Ayaan Hirsi Ali, Theo van Gogh, 2007 (Box 16, Folder 92)
  - Anti-Semitism in France, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 93)
  - Anti-Semitism, religion in U.S., 2002 (Box 16, Folder 94)
  - Anti-Semitism, religion in U.S., 2002 (Box 16, Folder 95)
  - Anti-Semitism, religion in U.S., 2002 (Box 16, Folder 96)
  - Anti-Semitism, religion in U.S., 2002 (Box 16, Folder 97)
  - Aronson 'Sartre/Camus' 2004 NYR, circa 2003 (Box 16, Folder 98)
  - Camus, Sartre and Aronson, circa 2003 (Box 16, Folder 99)
  - Cold War, 2000 (Box 16, Folder 100)
  - DIIS Working Paper, 2007 (Box 16, Folder 101)
  - Downs, Laura, articles, 2005-2006 (Box 16, Folder 102)
  - Dunn, John, typescript, notes, undated (Box 16, Folder 103)
  - Dunn, John, typescript, notes, undated (Box 16, Folder 104)
  - Empire? (U.S. post-9/11, Iraq), 2003 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Empire? (U.S. post-9/11, Iraq), 2003 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Empire? (U.S. post-9/11, Iraq), 2003 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Empire? (U.S. post-9/11, Iraq), 2003 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Empire? (U.S. post-9/11, Iraq), 2003 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Empire? (U.S. post-9/11, Iraq), 2004 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Empire? (U.S. post-9/11, Iraq), 2004 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Empire? (U.S. post-9/11, Iraq), 2004 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Empire? (U.S. post-9/11, Iraq), 2004 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Empire? (U.S. post-9/11, Iraq), 2004 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Empire? (U.S. post-9/11, Iraq), 2004 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Empire? (U.S. post-9/11, Iraq), 2004 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Empire? (U.S. post-9/11, Iraq), 2004 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Eurobarometer 1998, circa 2002 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Eurobarometer 2000-on racism and xenophobia, circa 2001 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Eurobarometer 2000-on racism and xenophobia, circa 2001 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Eurobarometer 2000-on racism and xenophobia, circa 2001 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Eurobarometer 2002 [prelim], circa 2002 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Flash Eurobarometer-International Crisis, circa 2001 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Flash Eurobarometer-International Crisis, circa 2001 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Flash Eurobarometer-International Crisis, circa 2001 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Fleming, Katherine, articles, circa 2000-2001 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - France - untitled notes, circa 2005 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - French Communism, 1997-1998 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Globalisation and Opponents, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Government Accountability in East Central Europe report, circa 2002 (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Gross, Jan, Neighbors draft, undated (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - Gross, Jan, Neighbors draft, undated (Box 17, Folder 28)
  - Gross, Jan, Neighbors draft, undated (Box 17, Folder 29)
  - Gross, Jan, Neighbors draft, undated (Box 17, Folder 30)
  - Hungarian Research - Magyar [trials?], circa 1988 (Box 17, Folder 31)
  - Hungarian Research - Magyar [trials?], circa 1988 (Box 17, Folder 32)
  - Hungarian Research - Berend book, circa 1988 (Box 17, Folder 33)
  - Hungarian Research - Kapu, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 34)
  - Hungarian Research - Kapu, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 35)
  - Hungarian Research - Zuglói Nyilasper, undated (Box 17, Folder 36)
  - Hungarian Research - Társadalmi Szemle, undated (Box 17, Folder 37)
  - Hungarian Research - Társadalmi Szemle, undated (Box 17, Folder 38)
  - Hungarian Research - Társadalmi Szemle, undated (Box 17, Folder 39)
  - Hungarian Research - Társadalmi Szemle, undated (Box 17, Folder 40)
  - Hungarian Research - Társadalmi Szemle, undated (Box 17, Folder 41)
  - Hungarian Research - Szabad Nép, undated (Box 17, Folder 42)
  - Hungarian Research - Szabad Nép, undated (Box 17, Folder 43)
  - Hungarian Research - Szabad Nép, undated (Box 17, Folder 44)
  - Hungarian Research - Szabad Nép, undated (Box 17, Folder 45)
  - Hungarian Research - Szabad Nép, undated (Box 17, Folder 46)
  - Hungarian Research - Szabad Nép, undated (Box 17, Folder 47)
  - Hungarian Research - Szabad Nép, undated (Box 17, Folder 48)
  - Hungarian Research - Szabad Nép, undated (Box 17, Folder 49)
  - Hungarian Research - Szabad Nép, undated (Box 17, Folder 50)
  - Iraq War and Europe, 2002-2003 (Box 17, Folder 51)
  - Iraq War and Europe, 2002-2003 (Box 17, Folder 52)
  - Iraq War and Europe, 2002-2003 (Box 17, Folder 53)
  - Iraq War and Europe, 2002-2003 (Box 17, Folder 54)
  - Israel Forum Talk, 2004 (Box 17, Folder 55)
  - Israel Forum Talk, 2004 (Box 17, Folder 56)
  - Israel Forum Talk, 2004 (Box 17, Folder 57)
  - Israel Forum Talk, 2004 (Box 17, Folder 58)
  - Israel Forum Talk, 2004 (Box 17, Folder 59)
  - Italian Fascists, 2000-2001 (Box 17, Folder 60)
  - Italian Fascists, 2007 (Box 17, Folder 61)
  - Jüdisches Museum Frankurt am Main exhibition book, circa 2007-2010 (Box 17, Folder 62)
  - Kosicki, Piotr H., typescript, undated (Box 17, Folder 63)
  - Kosicki, Piotr H., typescript, undated (Box 17, Folder 64)
  - LRB + NYR letters, 2006 (Box 17, Folder 65)
  - Misc., circa 2007-2008 (Box 17, Folder 66)
  - Misc. annotated articles, undated (Box 17, Folder 67)
  - Misc. annotated articles, undated (Box 17, Folder 68)
  - Misc. annotated articles, undated (Box 17, Folder 69)
  - Misc. articles, 2003-2007 (Box 17, Folder 70)
  - Misc. articles, 2003-2007 (Box 17, Folder 71)
  - Misc. typescripts, undated (Box 17, Folder 72)
  - Misc. typescripts, undated (Box 17, Folder 73)
  - Misc. typescripts, undated (Box 17, Folder 74)
  - Newsweek, 2004 (Box 17, Folder 75)
  - Polish publications, 2009 (Box 17, Folder 76)
  - Rose, Peter I., typescripts, 2005, 2007 (Box 17, Folder 77)
  - Seidman, Michael, article proof, 2001 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Seigel, Jerrold, Modernity and Bourgeois Life, draft, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Seigel, Jerrold, Modernity and Bourgeois Life, draft, undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Seigel, Jerrold, Modernity and Bourgeois Life, draft, undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Spanish Civil War maps, undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Temkin, Moshik, The Sacco-Vanzetti Affair, excerpt draft, undated (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Temkin, Moshik, The Sacco-Vanzetti Affair, Judt report on manuscript, 2006 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Temkin, Moshik, The Sacco-Vanzetti Affair, manuscript, 2006 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Temkin, Moshik, The Sacco-Vanzetti Affair, manuscript, 2006 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Temkin, Moshik, The Sacco-Vanzetti Affair, manuscript, 2006 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Temkin, Moshik, The Sacco-Vanzetti Affair, manuscript, 2006 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Temkin, Moshik, The Sacco-Vanzetti Affair, manuscript, 2006 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Temkin, Moshik, The Sacco-Vanzetti Affair, manuscript, 2006 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Temkin, Moshik, The Sacco-Vanzetti Affair, manuscript, 2006 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Temkin, Moshik, The Sacco-Vanzetti Affair, manuscript, 2006 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Temkin, Moshik, The Sacco-Vanzetti Affair, manuscript, 2006 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Temkin, Moshik, The Sacco-Vanzetti Affair, manuscript, 2006 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Temkin, Moshik, The Sacco-Vanzetti Affair, manuscript, 2006 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Temkin, Moshik, The Sacco-Vanzetti Affair, manuscript, 2006 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Temkin, Moshik, The Sacco-Vanzetti Affair, manuscript, 2006 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Temkin, Moshik, The Sacco-Vanzetti Affair, manuscript, 2006 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Terror Haza brochure, 2002 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - UN Report: A More Secure World, circa 2004 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - UN Report: A More Secure World, circa 2004 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - UN Report: A More Secure World, circa 2004 (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - UN Report: A More Secure World, circa 2004 (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Untitled notes, undated (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Wehrmacht exhibit controversy articles, undated (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - Wehrmacht exhibit controversy articles, undated (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - Wehrmacht exhibit controversy articles, undated (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - Wehrmacht exhibit controversy articles, undated (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - Wehrmacht exhibit controversy articles, undated (Box 18, Folder 32)
  - Wehrmacht exhibit controversy articles, undated (Box 18, Folder 33)
  - Wehrmacht exhibit controversy articles, undated (Box 18, Folder 34)
  - Wehrmacht exhibit controversy articles, undated (Box 18, Folder 35)
  - Wehrmacht exhibit controversy articles, undated (Box 18, Folder 36)
  - Wehrmacht exhibit controversy articles, undated (Box 18, Folder 37)
  - Wehrmacht exhibit controversy articles, undated (Box 18, Folder 38)
  - Wehrmacht exhibit controversy articles, undated (Box 18, Folder 39)
  - West Bank separation barrier and settlements map, 2007 (Box 18, Folder 40)
- Series IV: Teaching Files
  This series is separated into two subseries.
  Subseries A: Class Material contains syllabi, readings and reading lists, and lecture notes from throughout Judt's teaching career. This material was culled from all over the collection.
  Subseries B: Student Files was a pre-existing grouping of files, so original order was maintained here and placed in Series IV: Teaching Files.
  - Subseries A: Class Material
    History of Socialism and Communism (1983)
    Fourier, Charles. Part II: Chapters II-IV in The Harmonian Man: Selected Writings of Charles Fourier, edited by Mark Poster. (Garden City, N.Y.: Doubleday, 1971)
    Saint-Simon, Claude-Henri de. Chapter VIII-IX in The Political Thought of Saint-Simon, edited by Ghița Ionescu. (London: Oxford University Press, 1976).
    Tristan, Flora. “To Working Men and Women,” Chapters I-IV in The Workers’ Union. (Paris: 1843).
    Photocopies
    Barry, Brian. “Is Democracy Special?” in Philosophy, Politics and Society – Fifth Series, edited by Peter Laslett and James Fishkin. (New Haven: Yale University Press, 1979)
    Berlin, Isaiah, “The Concept of Scientific History” in Concepts and Categories: Philosophical Essays, edited by Henry Hardy. (Oxford: Oxford University Press, 1980).
    Dunn, John. “Revolution?” in Western Political Theory in the Face of the Future. (Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 1979)
    Dworkin, Ronald. “Reverse Discrimination” in Taking Rights Seriously.
    Feinberg, Joel. “Is There a Right to Be Born?” in Rights, Justice and the Boundaries of Liberty: Essays in Social Philosophy. (Princeton: Princeton University Press, 1980)
    Feinberg, Joel. “The Nature and Value of Rights,” in Rights, Justice and the Boundaries of Liberty: Essays in Social Philosoph y. (Princeton: Princeton University Press, 1980)
    Finnis, J. “The Rights and Wrongs of Abortion: A Reply to Judith Thomson” in The Philosophy of Law, edited by R.M. Dworkin. (Oxford: Oxford Univerity Press, 1977)
    Judt, Tony. Introduction to Resistance and Revolution in Mediterranean Europe, edited by Tony Judt. (New York: Routledge, 1989.)
    Locke, John. Chapter V-VI in The Second Treatise of Government.
    MacIntyre, Alasdair. “Is a Science of Comparative Politics Possible?” In Against the Self-Images of the Ages: Essays on Ideology and Philosophy. (Notre Dame, Ind.: University of Notre Dame, 1978).
    Mill, John Stuart. “On Liberty: Of the Liberty of Thought and Discussion” in Three Essays.
    Raphael, David Daiches. “Grounds of Political Obligation” in Problems of Political Philosophy.
    Rawls, John. “Justice as Fairness,” in Philosophy, Politics and Society, edited by Peter Laslett and W.G. Runciman. (Oxford: Basil Blackwell, 1972)
    Rousseau, Jean-Jacques. Book II, Chapter I-XI in The Social Contract.
    Thomson, J.J. “A Defence of Abortion” in The Philosophy of Law, edited by R.M. Dworkin. (Oxford: Oxford Univerity Press, 1977)
    Williams, Bernard. “The Idea of Equality” in Philosophy, Politics and Society, edited by Peter Laslett and W.G. Runciman. (Oxford: Basil Blackwell, 1972)
    Loose Material
    Chapters from Them: Stalin’s Polish Puppets, by Teresa Torańska – sections on Edward Ochab, Roman Werfel, Jakub Berman, Appendix I, Appendix II
    Photocopies in French
    Juin, Hubert. “Le Silence D’Aragon,” Esprit 5, Mars 1957.
    Meray, Tibor. “L’Insurrection Hongroise et Le Drame D’imre Nagy,” in Les Temps Modernes, No. 141, Nov. 1957.
    Ostac, Robert. “La Yougoslavie de 1955,” Esprit 7, Juil. 1955.
    Péju, Marcel. “Chez Les Intellectuels De Pologne,” in Les Temps Modernes, No. 143-144, Jan.-Fev. 1958.
    Sarel, Benno. “Combats Ouvriers Sur L’Avenue Staline,” in Les Temps Modernes, No. 95, Oct. 1953.
    Sartre, Jean-Paul. “Qu’est-ce Que La Littérature? (suite), II: Pour Que Éscrit-on?” Les Temps Modernes, No. 18, Mars 1947.
    Sartre, Jean-Paul. “Qu’est-ce Que La Littérature? (suite)” Les Temps Modernes, No. 19, Avril, 1947.
    Sartre, Jean-Paul. “Qu’est-ce Que La Littérature? (suite) IV: Situation De L’Écrivain en 1947.” Les Temps Modernes, No. 20, Mai, 1947.
    Sartre, Jean-Paul. “Qu’est-ce Que La Littérature? (suite)” Les Temps Modernes, No. 21, Juin, 1947.
    Sartre, Jean-Paul. “Qu’est-ce Que La Littérature? (fin)” Les Temps Modernes, No. 22, Juillet, 1947.
    G46.2720 Topics in Twentieth Century Political Thought: Blum, Camus, Aron
    Blum, Léon. “La Division Du Parti Socialiste Le Congrès de Tours,” L’Œuvre de Léon Blum, Vol. III,i. (Paris: Éditions Albin Michel, 1972).
    Blum, Léon. “La Politique Sociale Du Gouvernement,” L’Œuvre de Léon Blum, Vol. IV, i. (Paris: Éditions Albin Michel, 1964).
    Blum, Léon. “Le Programme Du Rassemblement Populaire,” L’Œuvre de Léon Blum, Vol. IV, i. (Paris: Éditions Albin Michel, 1964).
    Blum, Léon. “La Réforme Gouvernementale,” L’Œuvre de Léon Blum, Vol. III,i. (Paris: Éditions Albin Michel, 1972).
    Blum, Léon. “Vie et Positions Du Parti Socialiste,” L’Œuvre de Léon Blum, Vol. III,i. (Paris: Éditions Albin Michel, 1972).
    Blum, Léon. “Souvenirs Sur ‘L’Affaire,’” L’Œuvre de Léon Blum, Vol. IV, ii. (Paris: Éditions Albin Michel, 1965).
    Judt, Tony. “The Lost World of Albert Camus,” New York Review of Books, October 6, 1994.
    Class Papers
    Brantlinger, Patrick. “A Response to Beyond the Cultural Turn.” The American Historical Review, Vol. 107, No. 5. (December 2002) p. 1500-1511.
    Geertz, Clifford. “Thick Description: Toward and Interpretive Theory of Culture.” The Interpretation of Cultures: Selected Essays by Clifford Geertz. (New York: Basic Books, Inc., 1973.) p. 3-30.
    Handler, Richard. “Cultural Theory in History Today.” The American Historical Review, Vol. 107, No. 5. (December 2002) p. 1512-1520.
    Hobsbawm, Eric. “Introduction: Inventing Traditions,” in The Invention of Tradition. Ed. Eric Hobsbawm and Terence Ranger. (Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 1983.)
    Hobsbawm, Eric. “Mass-Producing Traditions: Europe, 1870-1914,” in The Invention of Tradition. Ed. Eric Hobsbawm and Terence Ranger. (Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 1983.)
    Moravcsik, Andrew. “Chapter I: Theorizing European Integration,” in The Choice for Europe: Social Purpose and State Power From Messina to Maastricht. (Ithaca, N.Y.: Cornell University Press, 1998).
    Skinner, Quentin. “Meaning and Understanding in the History of Ideas.” History and Theory, Vol. 8, No. 1 (1969), 3-53.
    Suny, Ronald Grigor. “Back and Beyond: Reversing the Cultural Turn?” The American Historical Review, Vol. 107, No. 5. (December 2002) p. 1476-1499.
    Trevor-Roper, Hugh. “The Invention of Tradition: The Highland Tradition of Scotland,” in The Invention of Tradition. Ed. Eric Hobsbawm and Terence Ranger. (Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 1983.)
    “What’s Beyond the Cultural Turn?” The American Historical Review, Vol. 107, No. 5. (December 2002) p. 1475.
    - 18th c. lectures, undated (Box 18, Folder 41)
    - 18th c. lectures, undated (Box 18, Folder 42)
    - 18th c. lectures, undated (Box 18, Folder 43)
    - 18th c. lectures, undated (Box 18, Folder 44)
    - 18th c. lectures, undated (Box 18, Folder 45)
    - 4B Europe from Renaissance to 1815 - Winter Quarter, undated (Box 18, Folder 46)
    - 4B Europe from Renaissance to 1815 - Winter Quarter, undated (Box 18, Folder 47)
    - 4B Europe from Renaissance to 1815 - Winter Quarter, undated (Box 18, Folder 48)
    - 4B Europe from Renaissance to 1815 - Winter Quarter, undated (Box 18, Folder 49)
    - 4B Europe from Renaissance to 1815 - Winter Quarter, undated (Box 18, Folder 50)
    - Bibliographies - E. European and Jewish, undated (Box 18, Folder 51)
    - Bibliographies - E. European and Jewish, undated (Box 18, Folder 52)
    - Bibliographies - E. European and Jewish, undated (Box 18, Folder 53)
    - Bibliographies - General European, undated (Box 18, Folder 54)
    - Bibliographies - General European, undated (Box 18, Folder 55)
    - Bibliographies - Intell. History, undated (Box 18, Folder 56)
    - Bibliographies - Intell. History, undated (Box 18, Folder 57)
    - Bibliographies - Intell. History, undated (Box 18, Folder 58)
    - Bibliographies - Intell. History, undated (Box 18, Folder 59)
    - Bibliographies - Intell. History, undated (Box 18, Folder 60)
    - Bibliographies - Marxism, undated (Box 18, Folder 61)
    - Bibliographies - Misc., undated (Box 18, Folder 62)
    - Bibliographies - Misc., undated (Box 18, Folder 63)
    - Bibliographies - Misc., undated (Box 18, Folder 64)
    - France-Data for Socialism Lectures, undated (Box 18, Folder 65)
    - France-Data for Socialism Lectures, undated (Box 18, Folder 66)
    - Kriegel, Annie. Aux Origines Du Communisme Français, 1914-1920, Vol. 1., excerpt, undated (Box 18, Folder 67)
    - Photocopies - Berlin, Isaiah. "Two Concepts of Liberty", undated (Box 18, Folder 68)
    - Photocopies in French - Anger, Daniel. “En Bulgarie (Été 47),” Les Temps Modernes No. 29. Févr. 1948., undated (Box 18, Folder 69)
    - Photocopies in French - Biscarlet, Alfred. “La Marche Des Démocraties Populaires Vers Le Socialisme Et La Lutte Contre La Clique de Tito,” Cahiers du Communisme No. 2, 1950., undated (Box 18, Folder 70)